A Guide to the Papers of the University of Virginia Medical Alumni Association, 1939-1975
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
The Papers of the University of Virginia Medical Alumni Association 1939-1975
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
MS-21
1 linear foot, 2 document cases
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Unknown
Biographical/Historical Information
In 1939 the University of Virginia Hospital Development Office asked the Medical Alumni Association to assess the needs of each department and lab at the hospital. Included here are survey forms, filled out by department chairs. Other correspondence up to 1975 is included.
Scope and Content
The collection includes an extensive Report of the Department of Medicine of the University of Virginia to the Committee of Medical Alumni dated December 15, 1939 as well as committee correspondence and other documents.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Letter from Vincent W. Archer n.d., 1 TLS (Box-folder 001-001)
  Letter from Vincent W. Archer to National Medical Alumni Committee
- Report from Dept. of Medicine 12/15/39, 1TD, pp.1-64 (Box-folder 001-002)
  Report from the Department of Medicine of the University of Virginia to the Committee of Medical Alumni, part 1
- Report from Dept. of Medicine 12/15/39, 1TD, pp.65-130 (Box-folder 001-003)
  Report from the Department of Medicine of the University of Virginia to the Committee of Medical Alumni, Part 2
- Report from Dept. of Medicine 12/15/39, 1TD, pp.131-186 (Box-folder 001-004)
  Report from the Department of Medicine of the University of Virginia to the Committee of Medical Alumni, Part 3
- letter from John F. Anderson to Beverly C. Smith 3/25/40, 1TLS (Box-folder 001-005)
- Letter from John H. Dunningham to John W. Burke 4/4/40, 1TL, 1TD (Box-folder 001-006)
  Third year instruction in Ophthamology, Columbia University
- Letter from Carrington Williams to Beverly C. Chew 4/8/40, 1TLS (Folder 001-007)
- Summary of Activities 4/10/40, 1TD (Box-folder 001-008)
  School of Dermatology and Syphilology
- Letter from Francis H. Adler to John W. Burke 4/13/40, 1TL (Box-folder 001-009)
- Recommendations for Orthopaedic Department 4/15/40, 1TDS (Box-folder 001-010)
- Memorandum of needs 4/18/40, 1TD (Box-folder 001-011)
- Committee Agenda 4/19/40-4/20/40, 1TD (Box-folder 001-012)
- Address by H. E. Jordan 4/20/40, 1TD (Box-folder 001-013)
- Address by E. M. Landis 4/20/40, 1TD (Box-folder 001-014)
- Address by J. L. Newcomb 4/20/40, 1TD (Box-folder 001-015)
- Letter from J. W. Burke to Beverly C. Smith 4/29/40, 1TLS (Box-folder 001-016)
- Letter from W. S. Feathers to Beverly C. Smith 4/30/40, 1TLS (Box-folder 001-017)
- Report of Meeting 4/40, 1TD (Box-folder 001-018)
  copy
- Letter from Herbert Old to David R. Lyman 5/1/40, 1TLS (Box-folder 001-019)
- Letter from T. Duckett Jones to Beverly C. Chew 5/2/40, 1TLS (Box-folder 001-020)
- List of committee members [1940], 2TD (Box-folder 001-021)
- Recommendations of School of Neurology and Psychiatry [1940], 1TD (Box-folder 001-022)
- Interviews [1940], 13TD with AN (Box-folder 001-023)
  Interviews are with V. W. Archer, Department of Roentgenology; Samuel A. Vest, Department of Urology; Dr. Bray, Clinical Pathology; G. M. Lawson, Department of Preventive Medicine and Bacteriology; D. C. Smith, Dermatology; C. S. Lentz, Superintendent of the University of Virginia Hospital; Alfred Chanutin, Biochemistry; J. A. Waddell, Department of Pharmacology, Materia Medica and Toxicology; S. W. Britton, Department of Physiology; T. J. Williams, Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology; A. D. Hart, Director of Student Health; Dr. Funsten, Orthopedics; James Robert Cash, Pathology.
- Agenda, School of Internal Medicine by T. Duckett Jones April 19-20, 1940, 1TDS (Box-folder 001-024)
- Address by H. E. Jordan [April 19-20, 1940], 1TDS with AN (Box-folder 001-025)
- Address by E. M. Landis [April 19-20, 1940], 1TD with AN (Box-folder 001-026)
- Address by J. L. Newcomb, President April 20, 1940, 1TD with AN (Box-folder 001-027)
- Letter from John W. Burke to Beverly C. Smith April 29, 1940, 1TLS (Box-folder 001-028)
- Letter from W. S. Leathers to Beverly Chew Smith April 30, 1940, 1TLS (Box-folder 001-029)
- Report of Meeting of the Medical Alumni Committee, April, 1940 April 1940, 1TD (copy) with AN (Box-folder 001-030)
- Letter from Herbert Old to David R. Lyman May 1, 1940, 1TLS (Box-folder 001-031)
- Letter from T. Duckett Jones to Beverly Chew Smith May 2, 1940, 1TLS with AN (Box-folder 001-032)
- Letter from W. S. Leathers to Beverly Chew Smith April 27, 1940, 1TLS (Box-folder 001-033)
- Letter from Fletcher D. Woodward to H. E. Jordan 1/20/41, 1TL (Box-folder 002-001)
- Letter from Beverly C. Smith to Fletcher D. Woodward 1/21/41, 1TLS (Box-folder 002-002)
- Letter from Pate Fite to Beverly C. Smith 1/30/41, 1TLS (Box-folder 002-003)
- Letter from Development Fund 5/18/48, 1TLS (Box-folder 002-004)
  Letter from Development Fund to President Colgate W. Darden, Jr.
- Notes and reports 5/1/48-5/16/48, 1TD (Box-folder 002-005)
- Notes and reports 5/17/47-5/25/48, 1TD (Box-folder 002-006)
- Letter from Dr. Mulholland to Dr. Archer 8/31/48, 1TD (Box-folder 002-007)
- Bulletin 10/9/48, 1 bulletin (Box-folder 002-008)
- Letter from Colgate W. Darden, Jr. 11/3/48, 1TLS (Box-folder 002-009)
  Letter from Colgate W. Darden, Jr. to the Virginia Medical Alumni
- Development Fund Report [1948], 1TD (Box-folder 002-010)
- Letter from A. R. Shands, Jr. 4/10/49, 1TLS,1Brochure (Box-folder 002-011)
  Proposed by-laws for Medical Alumni Association
- Program 6/10/49, 1 Agenda (Box-folder 002-012)
- Letter from A. R. Shands, Jr. 6/20/49, 1TLS (Box-folder 002-013)
  Letter from A. R. Shands, Jr. to Medical Alumni Association
- Letter from C. B. Morton to William H. Wood 8/2/49, 1TL (Box-folder 002-014)
  dues notice
- Letter from C. B. Morton to James B. Twyman 1/5/52, 1TLS (Box-folder 002-015)
- Letter from James B. Twyman to C. B. Morton 1/8/52, 1TLS (Box-folder 002-016)
- Letter from C. B. Morton to James B. Twyman 1/10/52, 1TL (Box-folder 002-017)
- Letter from Vincent W. Archer to C. B. Morton 1/18/52, 1TLS (Box-folder 002-018)
- Letter from C. B. Morton to Vincent W. Archer 1/19/52, 1TL (Box-folder 002-019)
- The Newsletter 3/56-4/56, 3 tearsheets (Box-folder 002-020)
  pp.3-8
- Letter from James M. Moss to C. Bruce Morton 7/26/65, 1TLS (Box-folder 002-021)
- Origin and Early Days [1975], 1 Paper, 1 ATL (Box-folder 002-022)
  Origin and Early Days of the Medical Alumni Association of the University of Virginia by Beverly C. Smith; letter from Beverly C. Smith to William Booth